On the supply and demand of domestic tuna,
有關國產鮪魚的供給
we should apply our best efforts.
本公司也該竭盡所能
We're proposing a project called the Tuna Project.
因此以我們水產部為主體
I think that's a good idea.
這是個很棒的意見
But the fishery department should just stick to purchases.
但水產部能否只負責採購呢
What?
什麼？
You should leave the sales to our department.
擬定販賣策略並拿出成果 是我們的工作
That's no way to talk to your superior!
營業部的別插嘴
We've put a lot of preparation into this!
我們可是在漁業規制前 就擬好戰略了
Tuna is...
別小看鮪魚了
Okay. Then let me ask this.
請等一下，那我請教各位
Who sells the tuna that you buy?
採購來的鮪魚會在哪販售？
You should know who should take the initiative!
你們應該知道 握有主導權的是誰吧
Tuna belongs to the fishery department!
-鮪魚當然該交由水產部負責 -這是我們的專案
- Oh no! -Hot!
好燙
- Hot! - I'm so sorry!
燙死了
Hot!
很抱歉
My deepest apologies!
真的非常抱歉
Be careful because it's hot, okay?
很燙喔，小心點
Okay!
是
- Are you okay? - Yes.
-沒事吧？ -沒事
Thank you.
不好意思
Satonaka!
里中
What are you looking at?
你在看哪裡？
Come up with an idea for the sales team.
行銷課也和販賣二課一樣 提出一些點子吧
Yes, sir!
是
Fujii. Let's hear what you have to say.
再多談談吧
Putting together supply, circulation, and sales,
藉由掌握供給和流通、販賣
we can control the soaring prices and appeal to trading companies.
可以控制價格翻漲 讓更多的消費者…
Who's the temp that made us tea?
剛剛泡茶的派遣員工是誰？
Haruko Omae. She's from my section.
我們課的大前春子小姐
I blew it again!
我又搞砸了
Mori-chan. What happened this time?
小森，這次又怎麼了？
Please don't ask!
請別問了
Haruko...
春子前輩
Why am I always like this?
我到底為什麼會這樣呢？
The more I try not to mess up, the worse it gets.
每次想著不能失敗 身體反而變得硬梆梆
Mihara and Miya tell me
江原先生和美輪先生說
that it's a debt from my previous life.
這一定是上輩子累積的業報
I don't get what you're saying.
我不懂你的意思
Omae. Here are the documents.
大前小姐，資料送來了
Thanks for the tea earlier.
「謝謝你剛才的茶」
How about we grab lunch together?
「今天要不要一起吃午餐？」
What?
什麼？
"Email from Kishino"
（會議好無聊）
The meeting was boring so I couldn't help but looking at you.
「會議太無聊了 所以一直看著倒茶的你」
Hey!
等等…
Omae! You're so popular!
大前小姐竟然這麼受歡迎
- Let me see! - Look!
-我看看 -你們快看
"I eat lunch alone"
（我一向「自己」吃午餐）
Taking an upper-hand...
真是強勢
"Concentrate on meetings"
（請集中精神在會議上）
"You've got mail"
（收到新郵件）
He replied.
又寄來了
The red sweater looks good on you.
「紅色的毛衣很適合你呢」
I must be lucky to have you spill tea on me.
「能被你潑到茶 我真是個幸運男孩」
By the way, I'm free tonight.
「那今晚有空嗎」
Hold on a minute! You see that, Omae?
等等，大前小姐
Aren't those all addressed to Mori?
這些信都是要寄給小森的吧？
What? Me?
我嗎？
Then that'd make sense.
那就能理解了
They were sent to me.
這是寄給我的信
"That's none of your business!"
（別多管閒事）
Hey! Don't write that!
不行啦，前輩
They'll think I'm a terrible woman!
這樣會讓人以為我個性很差
It's a hassle to deal with these misunderstandings.
要解釋誤會太麻煩了
Omae, please stop!
討厭，前輩，快住手
What?
怎麼這樣
Thank you for your hard work.
辛苦了…
Full-time employee's pride comes before a fall.
傲慢的正職社員好景不常
Companies can't run without temp workers.
現在的時代，少了派遣員工 公司是無法經營下去的
Take Haruko Omae, for example.
就像這位大前春子
Impossible and overtime aren't words in her dictionary.
她的字典裡沒有 「不可能」和「加班」
She excludes all complicated relationships.
排除所有麻煩的人際關係
When her three-month contract is up,
當三個月的契約期滿時
she dusts herself off to somewhere else.
就會消失離去
But why this extraordinary temp worker, Haruko Omae,
但是沒有人知道
decided to choose this temp life,
超級派遣員工大前春子
no one really knows.
為何選擇成為非正職員工
"Pride Of The Temp"
派遣員的品格
Are you going to that restaurant again today?
今天也要吃定食嗎？
I actually can't eat by myself.
其實我沒辦法獨自在外面吃飯
Can I join you?
可以一起吃飯嗎…
- Kon! - Yes?
-近先生 -是
Can you eat lunch with me?
要不要一起吃午餐
I'm sorry, I brought my lunch today.
抱歉，我有便當了
Sorry.
抱歉啦
Lunchtime!
去吃飯吧
Let's go.
出發吧
Company cafeteria?
今天也吃員工餐廳
Meat and potatoes again?
你又要吃馬鈴薯燉肉了吧
Anything's fine.
吃什麼都好
I want curry rice.
我要吃咖哩
What are you looking at?
你在看什麼？
I was thinking...
那個，該不會…
Maybe you also don't like to eat alone?
黑岩小姐也沒辦法獨自吃飯嗎
What? That's absurd!
討厭，你在說什麼啊？
If you're okay with it, would you eat with me?
不介意的話，我們一起吃好嗎
What do you take me for?
你以為我是誰啊？
I don't have time to eat lunch.
我才沒有吃午餐的時間
I'm busy.
我很忙的
Rice ball from the convenient store again.
今天也要吃超商飯糰了
Mori.
森，我們要去員工餐廳吃飯 你要一起嗎
Chief, are you sure?
主任，可以嗎
I'm so glad!
太好了
Let's go eat then.
大家一起吃吧
Excuse me!
不好意思
Oh! Good to see you!
你好，受您照顧了
Can I join you for lunch?
-我也能一起吃午餐嗎 -當然可以
Thank you.
謝謝
So you can't eat out by yourself?
這樣啊 小森沒辦法獨自外食啊
It makes me nervous.
因為會很緊張，沒辦法
I feel like people are watching me eat.
感覺自己吃飯 就會被大家盯著看
It must be tough to be a woman.
當女生真辛苦
Some of them eat at diners by themselves though.
也是有女人可以獨自 若無其事地去吃定食
Are you talking about Haruko Omae?
大前春子嗎？
She's different from the rest of us.
她在我們的人員中 也是獨樹一格呢
It must be hard to work with her.
一木先生也很辛苦吧
You can tell?
你也懂嗎？
I don't get her at all.
老實說她實在不受控制
By the way, as for Omae,
請問…
what does she do on her days off?
休假時都在做什麼呢？
No one knows.
那是一團謎呢
I think she's backpacking abroad.
好像會自己去國外流浪
- Backpacking? - Yes.
-流浪？ -對
Travelling alone?
單身旅行啊
That must be lonely.
-不會很寂寞嗎 -對啊
is a special emotion to humans.
是人類才有的纖細情感
A lone wolf like her wouldn't understand.
孤狼怎麼會有情感呢？
Truth be told, she is quite far out.
坦白說，她根本不像人類
You've bottled this up for a while, haven't you?
你也積了很多怨言呢
You get it, don't you?
看得出來嗎
Going alone on trips, karaoke, movies, Korean barbecue.
再說啊，單身旅行，單人KTV 單人電影，單人燒肉
If you get used to that, you're done being a woman.
一個女人習慣了這些事 也就完蛋了
Omae doesn't seem to have many friends.
大前小姐好像沒有朋友呢
No friends that are humans, I'm sure.
她絕對沒有人類的朋友吧
Here. Please take this.
主任，請用
Thank you.
謝謝
Since when?
什麼時候…
What do you think, Kaori?
小香，這樣好嗎？
The new temp is after Satonaka!
里中主任要被菜鳥搶走了
- What? - So...
-什麼？ -所以說
we're going to let you in our clique.
讓你加入我們的派系吧
You can eat with us from now on.
下次跟我們一起吃午餐吧？
Okay! Gladly!
好啊，我很樂意
I'm Mori. Nice to meet you!
我姓森，請多指教
We're going to have more matchmaking parties this month.
這個月是我們的聯誼重點月份
I know it's sudden, but there's one tonight.
事不宜遲 我們今晚就要跟穀物部聯誼了
So this group...
大家的派系是…
Our main events are matchmaking parties.
我們的活動主要是聯誼
To find us husbands, of course.
目的當然是要釣個金龜婿
Let me do your hair.
我來替你捲
Omae!
前輩
They have the tuna meeting now.
待會要開鮪魚會議
And they want more tea.
所以要再多泡點茶
You stink.
好臭
Sorry. Is the perfume too strong?
抱歉，聞到香水味了嗎？
Yes.
聞到了
I can't be like the lone wolf like you are.
我沒辦法習慣 春子前輩的那種孤狼生活
So I joined a group.
所以加入派系了
What's that got to do with perfume?
這跟香水有什麼關係？
The group is very fashionable.
那可是個時髦派系喔
We're on our way to find us husbands.
目的是要釣金龜婿
I didn't join for that reason though!
但我的目的不是找金龜婿啦
Even so,
說是這麼說
you seem ready for the part.
但你很來勁呢
Oh, this? This is different!
這個？不是這樣的
They just wanted to do my hair!
這是剛剛她們在廁所 硬幫我捲的
Okay then.
那麼…
The first Tuna Project joint meeting is about to commence.
鮪魚專案第一次共同會議開始
First of all, how do we sell the tuna we purchase from fisheries?
首先討論水產部採購的鮪魚 要從什麼管道銷售
Let's go from there.
開始吧
The sales department suggests
營業部認為
I think that's a great strategy.
會是最好的戰略
- Agreed! - No objections!
-沒有異議 -贊成
It's decided then.
就這麼決定了
The marketing department can do some more research
如果大家都贊成 就請行銷課調查一下
if you agree.
開始銷售吧
Most sushi shops have their own venue to acquire their fish.
大型壽司連鎖店 有自己的採購管道
And 75 percent of domestic tuna is consumed at home.
加上國內有七成五的鮪魚 是家庭消費
The trend to eat tuna elsewhere has decreased rapidly.
外食吃鮪魚的趨勢正逐漸減少
Has decreased rapidly?
是減少納言嗎
Ogasawara.
小笠原先生
If you have any ideas.
有什麼想法請說吧
About raw tuna fish!
是有關生鮪魚的
What is it?
有什麼想法
I went to a shopping centre with my grandchild on New Year's night.
我在新年的時候 帶孫子去了購物中心
There was a tuna filleting show held by a tuna god, named Tsune.
當時有位 名為阿恆師的鮪魚之神
I ended up buying five bags of tuna.
我不禁就買了五份
And the tuna was absolutely delicious!
那個鮪魚真的非常好吃 好吃到快昏倒了
I'd understand if it were the fattier part of the fish,
我知道鮪魚中段和背脊 本來就好吃
but I was surprised that lean tuna could taste that good!
但沒想到連赤身都那麼好吃
I was utterly baffled.
真的是好吃到 不知道該如何是好
That's all.
以上
That's not a proposal but your personal feedback.
那不是提案，只是感想吧？
Oh, my apologies.
很抱歉，謝謝
That's brilliant!
不錯啊，鮪魚解體秀 就這麼辦吧
What? What about the conveyor-belt sushi shops?
-主任不是說要迴轉壽司？ -迴轉壽司怎麼辦？
Learn to switch gears, will you?
切換開關要快啊 開會不就是為了這個
The trading business needs a tuna filleting display!
消費者的需求是鮪魚解體秀
We have a venue for that, don't we?
也剛好有適合的 百貨地下商場
Representing the sales department, I'm going to make sure we succeed.
我代表營業部 一定會讓這個案子成功
Thank you, Ogasawara.
小笠原先生，謝謝你的好點子
Not at all.
-是 -謝謝你
Thanks in advance.
您好
"Display of a giant tuna in front of guests"
我們想以鮪魚解體秀 為主體舉辦活動
"A tuna god selling 500 tuna a year"
天啊
Tsune is selling 500 tunas a year?
阿恆師一年能賣五百條鮪魚啊
That's amazing!
真是厲害
His schedule has been full since half a year ago?
半年前就預約滿檔了？
Hello? Hello?
你好，你好？
They hung up.
掛斷了
Tuna filleting shows seem to be popular these days.
鮪魚解體秀好受歡迎啊
Yes.
真是不得了
I can't get a hold of him.
完全沒人能接
Just keep making calls.
總之只能一間一間問了
- Shoji! - Hey, chief.
-東海林先生 -主任
Here's the proposal.
企劃書完成了
Okay.
OK，你的工作就到這 可以回去了
Don't need you to tell me that.
不用你說我也會回去
Excuse me.
告辭了
- Thanks for the hard work. - Going home!
-辛苦了 -告辭了
Well done today.
辛苦了
Chief!
主任
Can I leave early today too?
我也能先回去嗎？
Thanks for your hard work.
辛苦了
Thank you!
-先告辭了 -辛苦了
Why did Mori join that kind of flashy group?
小森怎麼會加入 那麼花俏的團體啊？
Because people from Marketing are old and boring.
畢竟行銷課
Speak for yourself.
那是指小笠原先生你吧
Ogasawara!
小笠原先生
Please call these places today.
-今天請把這些電話都打完 -大受打擊
Did you use to go to matchmaking parties, Omae?
大前小姐 以前也很常去聯誼嗎？
Used to?
以前？
Sorry about the question.
前輩，不好意思
You look very experienced.
你看起來經驗豐富呢
If you know the secrets
聯誼的必勝方法
to matchmaking parties, please tell us.
如果知道的話請不吝指教
When comparing who's wiser among fools,
愚者比智慧
there's no winner.
半斤八兩
What?
啥？
What's she saying?
什麼意思？
What was that?
她是怎樣？
There are no guys like you at our department,
營業部才沒有帥哥
That's why we really looked forward to today.
所以我們今天 真的很期待看到大家
Really?
這樣啊？
Drink up! Cheers!
-大家今天… -阿恆師多喝點
Tsune?
阿恆師？
We're your diehard fans!
我們創立了阿恆師的 粉絲俱樂部
Today's tuna filleting show was brilliant!
今天的解體秀也好帥啊
Really!
真的
"Mr. Tsune"
（阿恆師）
Please excuse me.
我先離席一下
"Haruko Omae"
（春子前輩）
"Dialling"
（撥號中）
Omae? You won't believe this!
春子前輩，大事不好了
I'm at a matchmaking party.
我現在正在聯誼
And I bumped into him!
但遇到了不得了的人
My office hours are over.
今天的業務已經結束
Hey!
等一下啊
The turtleneck isn't here.
-今天套頭毛衣女不在呢 -你說誰？
Oh, nothing.
沒什麼
This is a nice place!
不過這間店真不錯
Tuna filleting display is a great idea!
「阿恆師的鮪魚秀」 這名字不錯
Glad you like it.
謝謝
Midorikawa from the department store said the same thing.
羅賓森百貨的綠川店長 也這麼說
Was that Omae's idea?
這是大前的企劃嗎
No, it was not!
不是的，部長
We just put Ogasawara's idea on paper.
這是小笠原先生的點子 再由我和里中策劃
Well, you'd better use her connections with the store manager.
據說她和店長的關係很好 一定要好好把握這點
Yes, sir!
是
Not me.
我就免了
Thank you for waiting.
久等了
Looks like you've finished this bottle.
已經空了呢
- Can we get one more of the same? - Sure thing.
-再給我一瓶同樣的 -好的
Well, is the girl who danced with a black dress here tonight?
請問
Oh, she's not in the mood to dance tonight.
她今天沒那個心情
I'm sorry.
真不好意思
I see.
這樣啊
Please enjoy.
請各位慢用
Haru-chan! Don't do this.
小春，這樣我很困擾
I need to get this out tonight.
今天我就直說了
How can you stand that lone wolf?
部長為什麼 那麼看重那隻孤狼？
Lone wolf?
孤狼？
Haruko Omae!
就是大前春子啊
I called her here because you both can't do your jobs!
因為你們太散漫了
What's so funny?
你笑什麼笑
Nothing.
沒什麼
That's not nothing!
哪裡沒什麼了
Sir,
部長
didn't you say at the new hire orientation
您在新人研修的時候說過吧
that the company is your home?
「公司就是家庭」
The employees are your family.
「而員工就是家人」
You said, "From today, you are my family."
您說「今天開始 你們就是我的家人了」
When I heard that,
我聽了那番話
I was so glad to be part of this company.
覺得能進這間公司真是太棒了
I see.
這樣啊
Temp workers are just strangers!
派遣員工只是外人罷了
They don't care what happens to the company.
他們一點都不關心公司的未來
They come and go as they please.
他們只顧著自己
I want to work with family.
但我想跟家人一起工作啊
Stop being so rigid!
別抱怨了
Times have changed. Acknowledge it!
時代已經變了，老實承認吧
What's the world come to?
怎麼會變成這樣呢
Maybe it's because we implemented business principles from America?
因為引進了美國的市場原理吧
Oh, so you get it.
你很懂嘛
And?
說看看
The business principles have to do with employees
市場原理就是自由競爭
and more relaxed regulations.
也就等於放鬆管制
Lowering the number of full-time employees as possible.
盡量減少正職員工
By using temp staff, companies can save a lot of money.
改用能讓經費減半的派遣員工 這就是必然的趨勢
I'm not asking about something so complicated!
我不是來聊這些大道理的
Just how it got to be like this!
我是問為什麼會變這樣
You've had a lot today, haven't you?
-你今天喝不少呢 -才沒有
Sorry.
不好意思
Hello, Mr. Asano? What's the matter?
你好，淺野，怎麼了
Mori has just called the office.
剛剛小森打電話回公司
Mr. Tsune that Ogasawara spoke about?
說小笠原先生提到的阿恆師
He's at a party with his fans in a restaurant in Ebisu.
正在惠比壽的餐廳 和媽媽粉絲們聯誼
The Tuna God?
鮪魚之神？
Okay.
我知道了
What?
怎麼了？
Mr. Tsune is in Ebisu.
-阿恆師在惠比壽 -真的？
Shoji!
東海林先生
Come on!
好
We'll go get Mr. Tsune!
我一定會跟阿恆師談妥
I'm counting on you!
靠你們了
So Mr. Tsune is alive and well.
原來阿恆師過得很好啊
Please, I'm begging you!
拜託您
People from my company will be here soon.
我們同事要來了
Could you please at least talk to them?
能請您聽他們說嗎？
Mori!
小森
Over here!
在這裡
Nice to meet you.
初次見面
I'm Shoji from S &amp; F.
我們是S&amp;F公司的人
No need for the card.
名片就不用了
If this is for an appointment, I'm already swamped right now.
如果要委託工作 我已經滿檔了
I'm sorry, but could you find someone else?
抱歉，你們能不能找別人？
This actually isn't work-related.
很抱歉，我們不是來談工作的
We're also a huge fan of yours.
我們只是阿恆師的忠實粉絲
I'm sorry to intrude on you all like this.
大家也是吧，真的很抱歉 我竟然這麼聒噪
My subordinate said she spotted you.
剛好我的部下說碰到阿恆師了
And I really wanted to talk about tuna with you.
所以就很想來跟您聊聊鮪魚
I was at your tuna filleting show during New Year's.
新年時我有去 購物中心的解體秀
I bought five packs of tuna!
還買了五包喔
The fatty part was delicious for sure!
除了鮪魚腹肉和背脊的部分 很美味之外…
- But the lean parts... - He's just repeating Ogasawara.
他竟然把小笠原先生說的 照著說了一次
I didn't know lean tuna could taste so good!
沒想到赤身竟然那麼美味
It made me want people to know about that lean tuna.
我真的是對赤身改觀了
You're right!
沒錯
He's right!
就是說啊
You understand, don't you?
你很懂嘛
I'm so glad to run into you!
好開心啊，是阿恆師
If you're okay with time, why don't we go to a different bar?
如果時間方便的話 要不要換間店再喝一杯呢？
You're all welcome to join!
太太們也請務必一起來
- Okay, group! - Yes?
美女軍團
Let's go with them!
一起去吧
He's great at this.
不愧是東海林先生
All of you are our guests!
大家一起喝一杯吧
It's a treat from S &amp; F!
S&amp;F要請客喔
I had a really good sleep.
昨晚真是謝謝你的招待
That's great. I had a lot of fun.
沒什麼，聊得好開心啊
- This way, please. - Okay.
這邊請
Attention!
各位，注意這邊
Let me introduce...
這位…
the Tuna God...
就是鮪魚之神
Mr. Tsune!
阿恆師，謝謝他來
Thank you.
請多指教
Could you get tea for us, Omae?
大前小姐，麻煩你泡茶
Okay.
好
As you can see, I only have a slot on Saturday.
如你所見
You're fully booked.
時間很趕呢
I'll start preparing right away.
我們會加緊準備的
Suzuki, the floor plan?
-鈴木，把平面圖拿來 -好的
Excuse me.
打擾了
Oh! Haru-chan!
小春
What?
咦？
Do you know each other?
你們認識嗎？
You see him?
看到了嗎
The real Mr. Tsune!
是阿恆師本人
All thank to you, Mori.
小森，都是你的功勞
Thank you.
謝謝
Chief...
主任
I'm sorry for running out like that last night.
真抱歉，昨天中途先離開了
It seems your values are different from ours.
感覺小森跟我們的價值觀不同
Who'd prioritize their jobs over a matchmaking party?
竟然把工作擺在聯誼前面
Last night was just a coincidence.
沒有啦，昨晚真的是剛好
Thanks for waiting. Let's go.
久等了，走吧
2,000 yen Italian detox course meal at the Marui Building.
今天要去丸之內大廈 享用兩千元的義式排毒餐
2,000 yen?
兩千元？
If it's good, let's go there every day.
如果好吃就每天都去吧
Who knows when this company will go down.
畢竟不曉得 能在這間公司待多久
Right?
就是啊
Are you coming?
你不去嗎？
Sorry. Can you go ahead?
不好意思，你們先過去吧
Sorry.
抱歉
What should I do, Haruko?
春子前輩，怎麼辦
I've been invited to a 2,000-yen lunch.
她們邀我去吃兩千元的午餐
If this continues everyday--
要是每天都這樣的話
You'll be broke.
會破產吧
But if I refuse, I'll become alone again.
但要是拒絕她們
I had just found some friends to have lunch with.
好不容易找到 可以一起吃午餐的朋友
Are you friends just because you do the same things?
只是一起做同一件事 就算朋友嗎
You poor thing.
真可憐
Those aren't friends.
那根本稱不上朋友
They're goldfish faeces.
不過是金魚的排泄物罷了
Then what are real friends like?
那真正的朋友是什麼呢？
Why do you ask such a dumb question?
那算什麼…
Well, you don't seem to have any friends.
因為
So what?
那又怎樣？
So you don't know how I feel!
你才不了解我的心情呢
Then don't come to me for advice.
那就別找我商量啊
The second person was a joke!
那個人真的不行吧，第二個
- The one with glasses? - Yes!
-戴眼鏡的對吧？ -對
Thanks for having me.
謝謝招待，黑岩小姐
- It was so nasty! - Please excuse us.
-真的不行 -告辭了
- That's a major turnoff. - A major turnoff.
超在意的
That totally turns me off.
那種真的會讓人冷掉呢
That gets to me too.
我對那種的也是冷感
How about the guy next to him?
坐他隔壁的呢
The guy to his right?
隔壁的嗎，右邊？
"Robinson's"
（羅賓森百貨）
Sir.
店長
What do you think?
如何呢？
We didn't have much time, so we made these in half a day.
因為時間太趕 只用半天時間趕了這個
It's fine! Mr. Tsune really stands out.
沒問題啦 阿恆師大大地印在上面了
Didn't think you'd be able to catch such a big star like him.
不過真虧你們 能找到這麼紅的人
I tried my best.
費了一番功夫
There will be many observers from headquarters.
據說當天總公司 會有很多人來觀摩
- Headquarters? - Yes.
總公司嗎？
Mr. Tsune is really something!
不愧是阿恆師
By the way, where's Omae?
對了，今天大前小姐人呢？
Omae?
大前？
- Who's that? - Oh, come on!
-你說誰？ -別裝傻了
Jeanne d' Arc! Ms. Omae!
-那位聖女貞德大前小姐 -是在說她啊
That temp has nothing to do with this project.
那個派遣員工跟這個企劃無關
She's not coming on the day of?
-大前小姐那天不來嗎 -她不會來
That's right.
沒錯
Shoji.
東海林
Should I be worried?
沒問題嗎
What?
什麼？
Of course not!
那當然
All your floors will be flooding with people this Saturday!
店長，禮拜六一定有噴泉效應 二三樓的營業額都會倍增
Maybe you should clear up some more space.
-多增加一些警備吧 -沒問題嗎
Of course!
絕對沒問題
Why does everyone keep asking about Omae? It's so annoying!
每個人開口閉口都是大前 氣死我了
She likes to stick her nose in full-time employee's business.
那個女人的興趣就是 干涉正職員工的工作
I think you've got her all wrong.
東海林先生你誤會了
She's not that kind of a person.
大前小姐不是那種人
What are you saying?
什麼嘛
Are you saying you know her that well?
小賢你很了解套頭毛衣女嗎？
Why won't you say something?
為什麼不說話？
She's a black hole!
那個套頭毛衣女可是黑洞
She sucks the energy out of others and uses it for her benefit.
她會藉由重力 將很多東西吸進去
You better watch yourself!
小心點啊
She's not like that!
大前小姐
Stop talking about her already!
就說別一直大前大前的叫 吵死了
I'm Omae.
敝姓大前
You were saying?
有問題嗎
I can't get away no matter where I go!
又出現了 不管走到哪都會遇到大前
Hey!
你是怎樣？
Were you following us? Were you eavesdropping?
你是不是跟著我們 還是在偷聽啊？
It's not like that!
不是啦
This is where you catch your bus, isn't it?
大前小姐要在這搭公車對吧
Bus? Busses are for humans!
公車？公車是人類在搭的
She can teleport, I'm telling you!
黑洞只要瞬間移動就好了
Anyway,
話說回來
your hair looks like the universe exploded.
東海林先生的髮型 真的像大爆炸一樣
What are you're talking about, you black hole!
少給我冷靜地說這種 莫名其妙的話，你這個黑洞女
We've still got work to do!
我們還有工作
Be careful of her, Ken-chan!
小賢你小心點
You never know when she'll teleport!
不管去哪 她都會瞬間移動追上來的
Teleport!
這個黑洞會瞬間移動
It's huge!
好大條啊
How heavy is this?
這有幾公斤？
73 kilograms.
73公斤
That heavy?
73公斤？
You can sell all of these?
這些真的能全部賣掉吧？
Are you sure?
真的沒問題吧
You don't trust my skills?
你不相信我的手腕嗎
It's not that.
不是這樣的
People from the department store headquarters will arrive tomorrow.
因為百貨總公司的人 明天也會來觀摩解體秀
I'll get in trouble if I don't show good results.
如果沒有拿出好成績 我們就要負責任了
You idiot!
混帳
- What? - You've got it all wrong!
-什麼？ -你根本搞不清楚狀況
I sell tuna to make the customers happy.
我是為了讓客人們開心 才賣鮪魚的
The headquarters?
什麼總公司還是成果 都跟我無關
Don't matter? I'm trying hard here.
怎麼能說無關 我們可是拼了命的
I can see through you.
我看清你的本性了
You say a bunch of nice things when you want something.
只有在有求於人時 才會說些好聽話
I'm done here.
我走了
Please wait a minute!
請等一下
Let go!
放開我
Mr. Tsune!
阿恆師
- Are you okay? - Don't touch me!
-沒事吧？ -別碰我
I'm sorry!
阿恆師
Ambulance! Are you okay?
救護車，沒事吧？
Someone call an ambulance!
-別碰我 -快叫救護車
Are you okay, Mr. Tsune?
沒事吧？阿恆師
Hey!
撐住
What?
什麼？
Broken right shoulder?
右手骨折？
It happened under my watch.
我跟在他身邊還發生這種事
I'm so sorry.
非常抱歉
What will happen to the show?
解體秀要怎麼辦？
We have until tomorrow
總之在明天之前
to find a replacement for Mr. Tsune.
要找到阿恆師的代打
Midorikawa at the store is helping too.
綠川先生願意等我們
I see.
這樣啊
We have ten 70 kilogram tunas.
共有10尾70公斤的黑鮪魚
They will be shipped out by tonight.
今晚就會從市場送到百貨公司
We also made adverts.
廣告也已經打出去
We can't back out now.
沒有退路了
And?
真的…
Are you okay with this?
沒問題吧？
I'll make it happen.
-我一定會設法解決 -好
I'll go to the main company and catch up later.
我也去總部追蹤狀況
Sorry about this.
非常抱歉
Are you sure we can pull this off?
主任，真的還能辦嗎？
We can't find a replacement for Mr. Tsune by tomorrow.
明天之前不可能找到人 代替阿恆師的
What are you talking about?
說什麼傻話？
If we say we're doing something, we do it!
說要辦就是要辦
I was opposed from the beginning!
我其實是反對的
We should've just bought frozen tuna.
早知道用冷凍鮪魚就好了
You guys are terrible!
你們真的爛透了
You all bail when the ship is sinking?
船要沉了就趕著逃命是嗎
Okay.
我明白了
Do your own work.
你們就做好自己的工作吧
I'll be fine on my own.
一定有辦法的
Shoji.
東海林先生
The marketing department will support you.
行銷課會全面協助的
- Let's do this. - Thank you.
-一起加油吧 -謝謝
Yes, sir!
是
Omae?
你們也願意幫忙嗎
If it's during office hours.
-在勤務時間內的話 -小賢
Don't ask her.
那個人就算了
I don't plan on asking for her help.
我不打算接受你的幫忙
Shoji...
東海林先生
Whatever he said.
他這麼說了喔
We should reach out to sushi chefs.
這樣就要找一些料亭大廚 或是壽司師傅
Or whoever we can to help.
走一步算一步了
Shoji.
東海林先生
I'm so sorry, Ken!
抱歉啊，小賢
Don't worry about it.
算了，別在意了
- Let's go! - Okay.
-出發吧 -好
See you tomorrow.
先告辭了
Omae.
大前小姐
The tuna filleting display
解體秀…
is at 2:00 p.m. tomorrow.
是明天兩點
So?
那又怎樣？
You must have something up your sleeve.
前輩一定能想到 很棒的解決方法吧
I'm moved by Shoji and Satonaka's friendship.
里中主任和東海林主任的友情 讓我很感動
- So-- - I'm also asking you.
所以…
Everyone.
大家
Don't waste your breath.
別強人所難了
She doesn't do overtime or work on her days off.
她是不可能加班 或是在假日出勤的
Exactly. See you tomorrow.
沒錯，先告辭了
Okay.
再見
I'll help too. Let's do this.
今天我也來幫忙吧，加油
Is this Sakauchi?
是榮壽司嗎？
This is S &amp; F calling.
我們是S&amp;F公司
Here!
問這間吧
- Please help us. - Please.
-拜託您了 -拜託了
I'm busy here. Go home.
我們很忙，快回去
Please, we really need your help.
能請您想想辦法嗎？
Please!
拜託您
I said, go home.
叫你們回去了
I'm busy tomorrow.
明天沒辦法呢，我們也很忙
Please, we need your help.
能請您想想辦法嗎
Please!
拜託了
We know we're asking a lot.
我們也明白這很強人所難
It's Saturday, so can't do.
-抱歉，明天是禮拜六 -拜託
This tuna looks amazing!
真是漂亮的鮪魚
You're still here?
店長，你還在啊
I can't get my mind off tomorrow.
我太擔心明天的事了
Should we unload these? You're Nakazato?
先卸貨吧，你叫中里嗎
- I'm Satonaka. - Oh, Satonaka. Here.
我是里中
Ready?
-一起搬吧 -是
Who's replacing Mr. Tsune?
阿恆師的代打是怎樣的人？
- What? - That...
什麼？
What kind of person is he?
是怎樣的人？
Hey!
喂
You haven't found anyone yet?
還沒找到人嗎
I'm so sorry!
非常抱歉
We'll be fine.
沒問題的
We still have 12 hours.
還有12個小時
Nakazato.
中里
Tell him.
我把話講白了
It's not just his head on the line.
不只這傢伙
They'll have my head too!
我也會被炒魷魚的
Too bad.
很可惜
They were out of yakisoba rolls.
沒有賣炒麵麵包
No one's open at this hour.
這種時間怎麼會有
Here.
來
I may be done for.
這下我也完蛋了
It's too soon to give up!
現在放棄還太早了
You've been through times like this.
你以前… 不也撐過了許多次危機嗎
Let's try Tsukiji!
去築地河岸問看看吧
I'm sure we'll find someone there.
那裡一定能找到人的
I know you're trying hard, Ken.
小賢，雖然你這麼努力
But I'm not giving you credit for this.
我可不會把功勞讓給你
Let's go, Shoji!
我們走吧
Shoji?
東海林先生？
Those men from your office the other day.
小春，前陣子 你公司的人有來吧？
Which one would you fancy?
裡面你喜歡哪一個？
What about you?
你呢？
Me?
我嗎？
If you ask me...
我啊
They have to be good-looking. I like good-looking men.
還是會選帥哥，我喜歡好男人
Then maybe Satonaka?
那就是里中主任吧？ 但那個人啊…
He's cute but not a good worker.
長得帥但工作能力糟透了
How about the ugly one then?
那態度很差的那個呢？
The one with the crazy perm?
捲捲頭嗎？
He is good at his job, but...
雖然那傢伙很會做事
has prejudice against temps.
但歧視派遣員工
That's shocking to hear.
好震驚啊
Who are you talking about?
等等，你在說哪個？
The one with the perm, of course.
我嗎？當然是捲捲頭
He's not good-looking at all!
根本不是看臉嘛
- Really? - Well, beauty is subjective.
-是嗎？ -畢竟審美觀因人而異嘛
- True. - I guess.
也對
The crazy perm, huh?
捲捲頭…
Sorry for the sudden visit.
很抱歉突然打擾
The one that's not my type.
不是我的菜的那位
Sorry?
咦？
Hello, Satonaka.
你好，里中先生
Is Omae here?
大前小姐在嗎
Omae.
大前小姐
I've come to ask for a favour.
我有事想拜託你
The tuna filleting show has been cancelled.
鮪魚解體秀要中止了
We couldn't find
我們找不到
anyone to replace Mr. Tsune.
能代替阿恆師的人
This will be a huge loss for the department store.
百貨公司將面臨巨大的損失
I'm on my way there to apologise.
我們待會要去道歉
I heard that the store manager trusts you.
你深受店長的信賴
Would you mind coming with me?
能請你一起來嗎？
I...
我…
From the time I joined the company,
從進公司以來
Shoji has taken care of me.
就很受東海林先生照顧
I want to return the favour.
我希望能幫上他
What a beautiful friendship.
真是美麗的友情
But...
但是
I don't think that's something
為此來拜託身為派遣員工的我
you need to ask from a temp like me.
我覺得沒道理
Stop blurring the lines between business and personal life.
請別把工作和私情混為一談
Omae.
大前小姐
I'm begging you.
拜託你
Please leave.
請回吧
Shoji.
東海林先生？
I've made up my mind.
我已經做好覺悟了
"Letter of resignation"
（辭職信）
Please! Omae!
拜託了，大前小姐
When I say no,
我說要拒絕
it means no.
就是會拒絕
He's about to resign!
東海林先生已經寫好辭職信了
No one loves the company more than he does.
沒有人比他更熱愛公司了
I just want to help him somehow!
我想幫助他啊
Please leave.
請回吧
I'm sorry for raising my voice.
抱歉吵到你們了
I'll be going now.
告辭了
Are you sure about this, Haru-chan?
小春，這樣好嗎？
Yes.
你好
Haru-chan?
是小春嗎？
Mr. Tsune?
阿恆師？
I kind of messed things up.
重要的現場表演得開天窗了
And I'm getting old.
我也老了
I think it's time for me to retire.
黃金時代已經過了
Mr. Tsune.
阿恆師
"Robinson's"
（羅賓森百貨）
We're deeply sorry!
真的非常抱歉
The tuna filleting display today has been cancelled.
今天的解體秀
What?
怎麼會…
We're truly sorry!
非常抱歉
Sorry!
對不起
We're deeply sorry!
非常抱歉…
We are very sorry.
真的很抱歉
My company will take full responsibility.
這次的責任
No time for that!
總之
Just think of how to get through this!
先想想怎麼撐過這個場面吧
Oh, it's senior manager!
本部長
Mr. Kirishima.
桐島先生
What's going on here?
這究竟是怎麼回事？
Sir.
本部長
About today,
這些損失我們會…
I'm truly sorry...
真的非常抱歉
What's going on?
開什麼玩笑
We are deeply sorry about this!
真的
We're very sorry!
非常抱歉
May I have your attention, please.
各位親愛的貴賓
From now, at the basement sales corner,
於地下食品賣場
on the special stage,
特別舞台
a tuna filleting display is about to begin.
現在即將舉行鮪魚解體秀
What's going on?
-什麼？ -要辦嗎
What?
還是會辦嘛
Haruko?
春子前輩？
Omae?
大前小姐
It can't be her.
套頭毛衣女
Now...
各位貴賓
at the basement food corner,
於地下食品賣場的特別舞台
Haru's tuna filleting display is about to begin.
小春的鮪魚解體秀
Come one, come all! Loosen your money purses!
快來瞧瞧
Let's begin!
你們瞧
Look at this tuna!
看看，這條鮪魚很大尾吧？
It's a 73 kilogram tuna!
73公斤的黑鮪魚
I cannot wait to fillet this tuna!
即將開始舉行 會讓大家想買到不得了的
Let the show begin!
小春鮪魚解體秀
Take a good look!
各位請看這個油脂
Isn't this fresh?
很漂亮吧
Aren't you excited?
真讓人開心對吧
Yes!
好開心
If you're excited, then I'm excited!
各位開心我就開心
Happiness needs to be shared.
這個世界上，快樂是會分享的
Take a bite of this tuna and you'll know what happiness is!
這條鮪魚也因為 大家可以分享牠的美味
Even when you're down and out, happiness will come.
即使在人生的谷底 一定也能感受到喜悅
Okay!
很好
Like this leftover flesh.
請看這個背脊
This part is absolutely delicious!
這個部位真的好吃
Your luck will begin to turn after bad things go away.
口水往下滴，運氣跟著上升
The 100-yen deal is only good for today!
今天大特價，只要100圓
Who wants some?
有誰想要？
Me!
我要…
I want some!
我也想買
Paper, rock, scissors then?
那就猜拳決定吧
I'm going to be paper.
小春會出布喔
Paper, rock, paper!
剪刀，石頭，布…
I really put out paper! Okay, one more time!
我真的出布了呢，再一次吧
You all look so worried. One more time!
好難決定最後的贏家啊 那再猜一次吧
Paper, rock, paper!
剪刀，石頭，布…
Excuse me.
抱歉
Is Mr. Tsune out of the hospital?
請問阿恆師出院了嗎
Yes.
出院了啊
Do you know where he is?
-你知道他在哪嗎 -就在那裡
Thank you.
不好意思
Thank you very much.
這個，真是謝謝你
Come on, Mr. Tsune.
阿恆師你這樣不行啦
Be careful not to overwork yourself.
身體是一切的根本 得多注意點
I see you're working hard.
小春也很努力呢
Since that time.
從那時候開始
You were always so hard working.
你就一直很努力
Even on stormy days,
無論刮風
or snowy days,
或是下雪
you didn't complain at all.
你都沒有抱怨過
Haruko.
你啊
You were my best pupil.
就是我最棒的徒弟
Mr. Tsune.
阿恆師
You should listen to your pupils.
那你要聽徒弟說的話啊
What?
什麼？
We can work again when your injury is healed up.
等你治好了再繼續加油吧
There are many people who want to see you perform.
還有很多人想看 阿恆師的解體秀的
Okay?
好嗎
I guess you're right.
也對
Maybe I can put in a little more.
再努力一次看看吧
Yes, you can.
對啊
See you around, Mr. Tsune.
阿恆師，下次再見吧
Sure.
好
Take care of yourself.
小春也要保重喔
Okay. See you.
好，再見
See you.
再見
Omae!
大前
Don't be startled.
天啊
Thanks for your help.
得救了
Thank you very much.
真的很謝謝你
Kirishima will compensate you for special overtime.
桐島部長會支付 假日出勤的特別津貼
You can name your price.
無論多少都會付的
I'm sorry,
抱歉
but I don't want compensation.
我不需要津貼
Why not?
為什麼？
Because I wasn't working.
因為…
I didn't do that for S &amp; F.
我不是為了S&amp;F而去的
I did it for a friend.
而是為了朋友
A friend?
朋友？
Yes.
是
A fellow temp worker,
是我的派遣夥伴
Mr. Tsune.
阿恆師
But I thought you were a lone wolf.
你…
Mr. Tsune and I cannot allow sick days.
阿恆師和我 都不會讓工作開天窗
It's like walking on blades every day.
因為每天都像是走在鋼索上
It's natural for people like us to help each other.
有這樣的夥伴
That's all I have to say.
以上就是我的原因，可以嗎
- She's late. - The line's going to be long!
-她好慢喔 -對啊
You're late.
你好慢喔
I'm sorry.
對不起
I...
我…
I won't be going.
不去了
I've tried blending in with you all.
能跟各位吃飯讓我很有面子
But I can't afford to be eating 2,000-yen lunches.
但我沒有餘力吃兩千元的午餐
The truth is.
其實我…
I was just lonely and didn't want to eat lunch by myself.
只是因為怕寂寞 所以沒辦法一個人吃飯罷了
But I'm going to try that from now.
但是我會自己努力的
Thanks for waiting.
久等了
Kuroiwa.
黑岩小姐 今天要請我們吃什麼？
What should we eat?
吃什麼好呢
- Thanks again. - Chinese, maybe?
真抱歉，總是讓你請
Hey...
那個…
I just want to thank you.
我得向你道謝
But...
不
Even before that, I have to apologise.
在那之前，我得先道歉
I misunderstood you.
我誤會你了
I mean...
應該說
My lack of trust for temp workers.
我不信任派遣制度
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Please forgive me.
請原諒我
You saved me.
你救了我一命
As I told our manager,
我跟部長說過了
that wasn't work.
-那不是工作 -我聽部長說了
He said that you refused compensation?
聽說你拒絕了特別津貼？
If it wasn't for money...
如果不是為了時薪
Then...
那為什麼…
you'd go out of your way like that.
會願意付出這麼多
It got me thinking.
我思考過了
Maybe...
也就是說
You did it for me?
是為了我嗎？
No...
不
Anyways...
總之
Thank you.
真的很謝謝你
That's my bus.
告辭了
"To be continued..."
（待續）
The workplace is no place for romance.
公司不是談戀愛的地方 是工作的地方
You know the girls I've dated before.
小賢你知道 我過去交往過的類型吧
She the total opposite.
可說是完全相反
So you're saying temp workers will always stay poor?
貧窮的派遣員工 是永遠脫離不了貧窮的吧
Hold it right there, Miyuki Mori!
那邊的森美雪，給我等一下